Finding Aid for John Tanton Papers 1960-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John Tanton Papers 1960-2007
Tanton, John, 1934-
1 oversize folder
25 linear feet
Environmental, population control, and immigration reform advocate; organization and litigation files relating to his various interests and activities; includes correspondence, legal documents, memos, topical files, and miscellaneous photographs.
861056 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Dr. Tanton (Donor No. 7087 ) in 1984.
Periodic additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is only partially open to research. Boxes 1-14 are open without restriction; boxes 15-25 are closed for 25 years from the date of accession, or until April 6, 2035
Dr. John Tanton is an environmental, population control, and immigration reform advocate from Petoskey, Michigan. He was born in Detroit, Michigan in 1934. Eleven years later, his family moved to a farm in Huron County. He attended Michigan State College and received his bachelor's degree in 1956. He received his M.D. in 1960 and his M.S. in ophthalmology in 1964, both from the University of Michigan.
Tanton has held leadership positions with many environmental groups and agencies. These include the Sierra Club, Michigan Natural Areas Council, Wilderness and Natural Areas Advisory Board, Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore Advisory Commission, Little Traverse Conservancy, and the Environmental Fund. He has also brought independent legal actions to prevent development of wilderness areas.
Tanton has also been active in population control. He was national president of Zero Population Growth, chairman of the Sierra Club's National Population Committee, founder of Northern Michigan Planned Parenthood Association, and has been active in Negative Population Growth, Inc., among other organizations.
In 1979, he created the Federation for American Immigration Reform (FAIR), of which he was chairman. FAIR seeks to end illegal immigration and to set a stable ceiling on legal immigration. In 1983, Tanton and Senator S. I. Hayakawa established an organization called U.S. English. It was created to combat bilingualism in the United States. He has been active in Immigration Reform Law Institute (IRLI) and Center for Immigration Studies (CIS).
Tanton has been active in conservative political causes. In 1989, he became co-founder of the American Alliance for Rights and Responsibilities (AARR), as a counter to the American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU). AARR is currently the Center for the Community Interest (CCI).
Tanton also has taken upon social issues such as gambling, health reform, and social security reform, among others. Beginning 1987 Tanton has been active in the Bringing Out the Best in Ourselves project, that constitutes a series of small grants to local public and parochial schools.
The papers of Dr. John Tanton consist of materials documenting his work as a political and environmental activist from 1960 through the 2000s. The portion of the collection open without restriction is divided into the following series: Personal/Biographical; Population and Immigration Organizations and Issues; Conservation Organizations and Issues; Topical Files and Activities; Correspondence; Politics and Government; and Social Issues. The portion of the collection closed to research until 2035 includes the continuation of several series: Correspondence; Personal/Biographical; Population and Immigration Organizations and Issues; Conservation Organizations and Issues; and one new series, Public Interest Organizations and Issues.
Subjects:
Alliance for American Rights and Responsibilities.; Birth control.; United States--Emigration and immigration.; Environmental Fund (U.S.); Environmental protection--United States.; Federation for American Immigration Reform.; Harbor Springs (Mich.); Michigan Natural Areas Council.; Monroe Creek (Mich.); Northern Michigan Planned Parenthood.; Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore Advisory Commission.; Sierra Club.; Tanton, John, 1934-; Michigan. Wilderness and Natural Areas Advisory Board.; Zero Population Growth, Inc.; Immigrants--United States.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Bear River (Mich.); Charlevoix County (Mich.); Emmet County (Mich.); Michigan. Wilderness and Natural Areas Advisory Board.; Monroe Creek (Mich.); Natural areas.
Contributors:
Graham, Otis L.
Genre/Form:
Aerial photographs.; Oral histories.; Photographs.
- Personal/Biographical
  The Personal/Biographical series contains general background material on Tanton and the various organizations in which he has been active. Included are an oral history transcript, newspaper articles, brochures, and Tanton's vita.
  - Biographical/memoir file, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Personal (includes clippings and vita) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous letters (Box 1)
  - Oral history interview of John Tanton conducted by Otis Graham (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous articles; letters to the editor (Box 1)
  - Eulogy written for Wesley Maurer, Sr. 1995 (Box 1)
  - Mitchell Prize essay: "International Migration as an Obstacle to Achieving World Stability" 1975 (Box 1)
  - Chevron Conservation Award 1990 (Box 1)
- Population and Immigration Organizations and Issues
  Population and Immigration Organizations and Issues is the series relating to Tanton's involvement with Northern Michigan Planned Parenthood, with Zero Population Growth, and with the Federation for American Immigration Reform (FAIR).
  - Northern Michigan Planned Parenthood 1965-1971
    - Abortion and population control (Box 1)
    - Abortion articles (Box 1)
    - Adoption (Box 1)
    - Board of Directors (Box 1)
    - Bylaws (Box 1)
    - Clippings (Box 1)
    - Congress (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Department of Natural Resources (Box 1)
    - Economics (Box 1)
    - Executive Director (Box 1)
    - Family planning (Family Enrichment Bureau) (Box 1)
    - Health Department (Box 1)
    - Marriage enrichment course (Box 1)
    - Michigan Planned Parenthood Affiliates' Committee (Box 1)
    - Michigan Population Commission (Box 1)
    - Michigan Population Council (Box 1)
    - Oakley, Deborah (University of Michigan School of Public Health) (Box 1)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity (OEO) (Box 1)
    - Planned Parenthood-World Population (national) (Box 1)
    - Planning and background (Box 1)
    - Pledge of social responsibility (Box 1)
    - Public affairs-region (Box 1)
    - Sterilization (Box 1)
    - Voluntary sterilization (Box 1)
  - Zero Population Growth 1974-1979
    - Agenda-Executive Committee (Box 2)
    - Board communications (Box 2)
    - Budget (Box 2)
    - By-laws (Box 2)
    - Committees (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Crime (Box 2)
    - Direct Mail (Box 2)
    - Dues increase (Box 2)
    - Economics (Box 2)
    - Equilibrium fund (Box 2)
    - Executive Director (Box 2)
    - Financial and legal (Box 2)
    - Financial statements (Box 2)
    - Goals statement (Box 2)
    - Grants, in and out (Box 2)
    - History (Box 2)
    - Immigration project proposal (Box 2)
    - International (Box 2)
    - Legal opinions/documents (Box 2)
    - Members survey (Box 2)
    - Michigan (Box 2)
    - Minutes and agendas (Box 2)
    - Minutes, Board (Box 2)
    - Minutes, Executive Committee (Box 2)
    - Only child (Box 2)
    - People and topics to bring up with them (Box 3)
    - Planning (Box 3)
    - Population education (Box 3)
    - Population policy (Box 3)
    - Prophylactics (Box 3)
    - Reorganization (Box 3)
    - Resolutions and policy statements (Box 3)
    - Resources Committee (Box 3)
    - Sex selection (Box 3)
    - Slogans (Box 3)
    - State level projects (Box 3)
    - Tax law changes (Box 3)
    - Teen pregnancy (Box 3)
    - Unemployment/growth (Box 3)
    - Welfare (Box 3)
    - Writings (Box 3)
  - Federation for American Immigration Reform (FAIR)
    - Topical files circa 1973-1981 (Box 3)
      (unprocessed)
- Conservation Organizations and Issues
  The Conservation Organizations and Issues series brings together various conservation and environmental groups and causes. These include the Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore Advisory Commission, files relating to the preservation of Sturgeon Bay Dunes and Sleeping Bear Dunes, Tanton's association with the Michigan Natural Areas Council, the Wilderness and Natural Areas Advisory Board, and the Mackinac Chapter of the Sierra Club. In addition, there are files pertaining to the Birchwood Suit and Monroe Creek Suit documenting Tanton's involvement with environmentally-related civil suits. Legal documents comprise the bulk of these last files, though there is also included here Tanton's correspondence with attorneys, other environmentalists, and the general public.
  - Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore Advisory Commission 1967-1980
    - Beaver Basin (Box 3)
    - Biographies, Commission members (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1967-1976, 9 folders (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1977-1980, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, Tanton 1974-1975 (Box 4)
    - Grand Marais Harbor (Box 4)
    - Miner's Basin (Box 4)
    - Minutes 1968-1979 (Box 4)
    - Printed
      - "An Economic Study," 1963 (Box 4)
      - "A Proposal," 1966 (Box 4)
      - "Master Plan," 1968 (Box 4)
      - "Development Concept," 1970 (Box 4)
      - "Review of Alternatives," 1980 (Box 4)
      - "Assessment of Alternatives," 1980 (Box 4)
      - "Draft General Management Plan," 1981 (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous (includes maps and brochures) (Box 4)
    - Publicity (Box 4)
    - Reports and Legislation (Box 4)
  - Sturgeon Bay Dunes
    - Topical Files circa 1976-1983 (Box 4)
  - Sleeping Bear Dunes
    - Topical Files circa 1972-1983 (Box 5)
  - Michigan Natural Areas Council 1960-1973
    - Constitutions and reports (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Membership lists (Box 5)
    - Minutes 1960-1963 (Box 5)
  - Wilderness and Natural Areas Advisory Board 1972-1975
    - Committee composition (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Criteria development (Box 5)
    - Fairlane (Box 5)
    - Minutes (Box 5)
    - Natural Areas Law (Box 5)
  - Sierra Club 1968-1978
    - Mackinac Chapter
      - Correspondence (Box 6)
      - Newsletters and mailings (Box 6)
    - Petoskey Area Group (Box 6)
    - Population Committee
      - Correspondence 1968-1977, 7 folders (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
      - Reports and proposals 1969-1978, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - World Population Year (Box 6)
    - Survival Committee (Box 6)
  - Monroe Creek Suit 1971-1975
    - Basic documents (Box 6)
    - Clippings (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Deeds (Box 6)
    - Expenses (Box 6)
    - Fundraising (Box 6)
    - Gleason's stream survey (Box 6)
    - Legal documents, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Birchwood Suit 1972-1978
    - Clippings (Box 7)
    - Correspondence (Box 7)
    - Promotional (Box 7)
      (mostly brochures and newspaper ads for Birchwood)
    - Legal Documents, 7 folders and loose materials (Box 7)
  - Thorne Smith (Box 8)
    - Topical Files circa 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Nature Conservancy
    - Topical Files circa 1974-1983 (Box 8)
  - Photographs
    Photographs relating to the Monroe Creek wetlands area in Charlevoix County, Michigan, the Birchwood Farm Estates and Bear River in Emmet County, Michigan, and of the members of the Wilderness and Natural Areas Advisory Board.
    - Monroe Creek (photos of the creek and wetlands) (Box 8)
    - Wilderness and Natural Areas Advisory Board (group portrait) (Box 8)
    - Birchwood Farm Estates (aerial photos of development site) (Box 8)
    - Bear River (Box 8)
    - Chevron Conservation Award (Dr. and Mrs. Tanton, 1990) (Box 8)
    - Land use, Michigan (slides) (Box 8)
  - Preserve Projects
    - Topical Files, A-H circa 1980s (Box 8)
    - Topical Files, I-Z circa 1980s (Box 9)
- Topical Files and Activities 1956-1983
  (mainly re conservation)
  The Topical Files and Activities series relates primarily to conservation organizations and issues in the period 1956-1983. Included is correspondence, published materials, and other documentation.
  - Abitibi Paper Company (Box 9)
  - Agricultural Land-Michigan (Box 9)
  - Americans United for Separation of Church and State (Box 9)
  - Bear River Development Commission 1966-1973 (Box 9)
  - Newspaper clippings 1967-1974 (Box 9)
  - Bear River Watershed 1964-1967 (Box 9)
  - Bottle Bill 1969-1983 (Box 9)
  - Common Cause (Box 9)
  - Conservation organizations (Box 9)
  - Consumers Power Company 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Craig Lake Reconnaissance Committee 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - Electric power (Box 9)
  - Energy crisis 1973 (Box 9)
  - Environmental Impact Statements-Michigan (Box 10)
  - Environmental Impact Statements-other states (Box 10)
  - Environmental Protection Act-Michigan (Box 10)
  - Escanaba River, Middle Branch Dam-Cleveland Cliffs Iron Company, Tilden Project 1972 (Box 10)
  - Fort Wilkins Natural History Association (Box 10)
  - Grass concrete (Box 10)
  - Harbor Springs 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - Hartwick Pines Natural History Association 1969-1975
    - Financial reports 1969-1979 (Box 10)
    - Fund raising (Box 10)
    - Legal (Box 10)
  - Highway rest areas (Box 10)
  - Highways (Box 10)
  - Interstate land sales (Box 10)
  - Land Sales Act 1972 (Box 10)
  - Land use planning (Box 10)
  - League of Conservation Voters 1970-1974 (Box 10)
  - Mackinac Shores Association (Box 10)
  - Michigan Basin Geological Society (Box 10)
  - Michigan Bell Telephone Company (Box 10)
  - Michigan Botanical Club (Box 10)
  - Michigan Environmental Protection Fund 1972-1977 (Box 10)
  - Michigan Land Use, Governor's Special Commission on 1971-1972, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Michigan Land Use Act 1972-1979, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Michigan Natural Resources Defense Committee 1969 (Box 10)
  - Michigan United Conservation Clubs (MUCC) (Box 10)
  - Michigan United Property Owners Association (Box 10)
  - Michigan wilderness areas (Box 10)
  - Mineral resources (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous 1976-1977 (Box 10)
  - Municipal forests (Box 10)
  - Names, addresses-miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - National Wildlife Federation (Box 10)
  - Natural Resources Commission, Department of Natural Resources-candidacy 1971 (Box 10)
  - Natural Rivers Act (Box 10)
  - The Northwoods Call (Box 10)
  - Nuclear reactors (Box 11)
  - Oil (Box 11)
  - Opal Lake Suit 1970-1974 (Box 11)
  - Parker Motor Freight Company 1973 (Box 11)
  - Parking garages (Box 11)
  - Penn-Dixie Cement Corporation-Petoskey Plant 1956-1974 (Box 11)
  - Pesticides (Box 11)
  - Petoskey (Michigan) (Box 11)
  - Petoskey (Michigan) Public Schools-Land Use Committee 1972-1975 (Box 11)
  - Planning and Conservation League (Box 11)
  - Planning conservation leagues (Box 11)
  - Political campaigns 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Real estate development 1971-1973 (Box 11)
  - Recycling 1971-1976 (Box 11)
  - Scenic roads (Box 11)
  - Sea Grant Program, University of Michigan (Box 11)
  - Sewage disposal 1969-1976 (Box 11)
  - Sewage disposal-Harbor Springs Area Sewage Disposal Authority 1970-1973 (Box 11)
  - Shorelands Protection Act (Box 11)
  - Snowmobiles 1970-1973 (Box 11)
  - Soil conservation-Michigan (Box 11)
  - Solid waste disposal (Box 11)
  - Tax laws (Box 11)
  - Three Lakes Association Suit 1973 (Box 11)
  - Transportation (Box 11)
  - United States Association For the Club of Rome (Box 11)
  - VISTIP (cable television) (Box 11)
  - Walloon Lake (Box 11)
  - West Michigan Environmental Action Council 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - The Wilderness Society 1958-1971 (Box 11)
  - Zoning
    - Airport, Emmet County (Box 11)
    - Bear Creek Township 1970-1972 (Box 11)
    - County level (Box 11)
    - Emmet County 1971-1981 (Box 11)
    - Federal level (Box 11)
    - Sanitary codes (Box 11)
    - State level 1970-1975 (Box 11)
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series dates from 1980 to 1994 and pertains to all of Tanton's organizational involvement.
  - June 1980-June 1983, 35 folders (Box 12)
  - July 1983-June 1985, 24 folders (Box 13)
  - July 1985-August 1991, 22 folders (Box 14)
  - September 1991-December 1994, 20 folders (Box 15)
    (Closed until April 6, 2035 )
  - 1995-1997, 20 folders (Box 16)
  - 1998-2001, 27 folders (Box 17)
  - 1973-2006 scattered, 12 folders (Box 18)
- Population and Immigration Organizations and Issues
  - Federation for American Immigration Reform (FAIR)
    - Board of Advisors and Board of Directors
      - Board of Advisors 1979-1980, 1983-1992, 1998, 4 folders (Box 18)
      - Board meeting agenda 1979-1985 (Box 18)
      - Board meeting minutes 1978-1989, 1993, 1998-1999, 5 folders (Box 18)
        (On loan to donor)
      - Reports to the Board 1979-1996, 4 folders (Box 18)
    - Meetings
      - Summer Summit 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Summer and Spring Summit 1991-1993, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Finances
      - Laurel Foundation 1978-1983 (Box 19)
      - C.S. May Family trust 1983-1986, 1989 (Box 19)
      - Proposal Book 1985-1986 (Box 19)
      - Pioneer Fund 1981-1994, 9 folders (Box 19)
    - Publications
      - Correspondence 1979-1995 scattered (Box 19)
      - Ideas for topics 1978-1985 scattered (Box 19)
      - Topics 1981-1982 (Box 19)
      - Brochures 1980s-1990s, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - The Case for a Rational Immigration Policy, [1980 (Box 19)
      - The Chicken Little Media Scam, 1987 (Box 19)
      - Fact Sheet, 1981, 1986-1987 (Box 19)
      - Immigration Papers, 1980-1985 (Box 19)
      - Immigration Report, 1979/1980-1988/1989, 10 folders (Box 19)
      - Immigration report, 1990-1993, 2001-2004, 6 folders (Box 20)
      - In the News, 1986-1989, 4 folders (Box 20)
      - Immigration Issues in the News, 1991 (Box 20)
      - Information Exchange, 1982-1989, 1991, 9 folders (Box 20)
      - Press Releases, 1984-1991 (Box 20)
      - Sanctuary Information Packet, 1985 (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous, [1984, 1993 (Box 20)
    - Geographic file
      - Arizona 1984, 1988 (Box 20)
      - California 1981-1991, 5 folders (Box 20)
      - Illinois 1980-1989 scattered (Box 20)
      - Colorado 1981 (Box 20)
      - Connecticut undated (Box 20)
      - Florida 1975-1985 scattered (Box 20)
      - Iowa 1981 (Box 20)
      - Maryland 1980 (Box 20)
      - Massachusetts 1976-1989 scattered (Box 20)
      - Michigan 1979-1989 scattered (Box 20)
      - Minnesota 1981, 1992, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Missouri 1981 (Box 20)
      - Nebraska undated (Box 20)
      - New Jersey 1981-1982 (Box 20)
      - New Mexico 1981 (Box 20)
      - New York 1981-1993 scattered (Box 20)
      - North Carolina undated (Box 20)
      - Ohio undated (Box 20)
      - Oregon 1983 (Box 20)
      - Pennsylvania 1989, 1992 (Box 20)
      - Texas 1981-1991 scattered (Box 20)
      - Europe 1991 (Box 20)
  - Center for Immigration Studies (CIS)
    - Correspondence 1985-1989, 5 folders (Box 20)
    - Correspondence 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Publications 1988-1990 (Box 21)
  - Ford Foundation
    - Immigration Research 1985-1990, 4 folders (Box 21)
  - Gerry Mackie
    - Correspondence 1986-1990, 15 folders (Box 21)
  - WITAN (Box 22)
    - Meetings 1986-1988 (Box 22)
  - American Civil Responsibilities Union (ACRU)
    - Correspondence 1987 (Box 22)
    - Ideas and issues 1987 (Box 22)
    - Articles and accompanying material 1987 (Box 22)
  - American Civil Rights and Responsibilities Union (ACRRU)
    - Meetings 1987-1988, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Advisory letters 1987-1989 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence 1987-1988, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - People file 1987-1989 (Box 22)
    - Ideas and issues 1988-1989 (Box 22)
    - Articles and accompanying material 1987-1988, 3 folders (Box 22)
    - Program planning 1987-1989 (Box 22)
    - Weingart Foundation 1987-1989, 3 folders (Box 22)
    - Direct mail 1987-1989 (Box 22)
    - Cases
      - Rob Riley 1987-1988 (Box 22)
      - Legal cases 1987-1988 (Box 22)
      - Case statements 1987-1988, 3 folders (Box 22)
    - Publications
      - Information Exchange 1988-1989 (Box 22)
      - Newsletter materials 1988-1989 (Box 22)
      - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings 1987-1988 (Box 22)
  - Alliance for American Rights and Responsibilities (AARR)
    - Board of Directors
      - Records and correspondence 1989-1991 (Box 23)
      - Board meetings 1989-1990 (Box 23)
    - Meetings and conferences 1989 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence 1989-1991 (Box 23)
    - People file 1989-1990 (Box 23)
    - Ideas and issues 1989-1990 (Box 23)
    - Program planning 1989-1990 (Box 23)
    - Weingart Foundation 1989-1991 (Box 23)
    - Direct mail 1990-1991 (Box 23)
    - Annenberg project 1989 (Box 23)
    - Cases
      - Legal cases 1989 (Box 23)
      - Case statements 1989-1991 (Box 23)
    - Newsletter materials 1989 (Box 23)
  - Immigration Reform Law Institute
    - Board
      - Meetings and reports 1986-1990, 3 folders (Box 23)
      - Correspondence 1986-1989 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence 1985-1990, 4 folders (Box 23)
    - Publications 1989-1990 (Box 23)
    - Media clippings 1986-1987, 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Negative Population Growth (NPG)
    - Correspondence 1973, 1976, 1980-1991, 6 folders (Box 23)
    - Publications
      - The NPG Forum 1987-1991 (Box 23)
      - Human Survival 1981-1988 scattered (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous 1980-1991 scattered (Box 23)
  - Population Reference Bureau
    - Proposals 1983-1984 (Box 23)
    - California study 1985-1986 (Box 23)
    - California graphs undated (Box 23)
    - California Samizdat 1986 (Box 23)
    - Texas study 1986-1987 (Box 23)
  - LEADERS
    - Meeting 1993 (Box 23)
    - Prospectus and replies 1992-1993, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Clippings 1992-1993 (Box 23)
  - Growth and Development Forum (GDF) (Box 24)
    - GDF Committee 1989-1992, 1994 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence 1988-1992, 1994-1995, 5 folders (Box 24)
    - Bay Area Tomorrow 1988 (Box 24)
    - ACME project 1989-1991, 1994, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Information Exchange, 1988-1989 (Box 24)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences (AIBS)
    - Correspondence 1988-1991, 5 folders (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous publications 1986-2006 (scattered) (Box 24)
  - U.S.
    - Organization 1982 (Box 24)
    - Projects
      - E Pluribum Unum 1993 (Box 24)
      - Recycle North 1993-1994 (Box 24)
    - Finances
      - Statements 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Chart accounts 1991 (Box 24)
      - C.S. May Family Trust 1991-1993 (Box 24)
      - Donor Directed Fund 1993-1994 (Box 24)
      - Correspondence 1992-1993 (Box 24)
    - Cases
      - Arizonians for Official English
        - U.S. Court of Appeals 1993-1995 (Box 24)
        - U.S. Supreme Court 1995-1996 (Box 24)
- Public Interest Organizations and Issues
  The Public Interest Organizations and Issues series includes materials of organizations that combined social, political, immigration, environmental, and other causes on their agenda, as well as material on the subject of public interest. This series includes materials of a non-profit organization -- Bringing Out the Best in Ourselves, and materials related to the issues of gambling, programs for the partially sighted and individuals with low vision, charitable causes, the U.S. Constitution, and American politics and government.
  - Bringing Out the Best in Ourselves, correspondence 1987-1997, 6 folders (Box 24)
  - Gambling, correspondence about 1995-1996, 3 folders (Box 25)
  - Vision
    - Low Vision, correspondence about 1977-1979 (Box 25)
    - Lighthouse for Partially Sighted, correspondence 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Politics and government
    - Unicameral legislature 1971-1972 (Box 25)
    - Bicentennial of the U.S. Constitution 1986-1987 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Projects and Publications 1979-1981, 1983-1987 (Box 25)
- Conservation Organizations and Issues